Meier mss., 1927-2010
Indiana University Digital Library Program
- Writings and speeches, 1955-2009, undated (Box 5)
  - Drafts and notes for articles and speeches, 1955-2008, undated (Box 9)
    - In the name of a return to basics we are witnessing a massive forgetfulness..., undated, 2 drafts
    - Fortunately, unfortunately, why schools so important?..., undated
    - There's an interesting trend afoot in education that corresponds--hardly surprising--with a larger societal one. In the simplest lay language it involves taking away important powers from teachers and local schools..., undated
    - Stop, I want to get off! Just let me be! Surely I should be happy that education is news again..., undated
    - Draft fragment, p. 10, Alternatives, (3) school of choice..., undated
    - I accepted this offer for the oddest reason..., undated
    - I. What's the idea--the fairly contemp concept..., undated
    - Draft fragment, p. 2-8, 1. Public education as we think of it--the idea that everyone should get an equal education at public expense--is a new idea..., undated
    - Draft fragment, p. 2-16, Idea of public ed (equal educ at public expense) 100 as idea, 50 as semi practice..., undated
    - Public education--the notion that everyone deserves an equal education at public expense--is both a new idea--and a very shakey one..., undated
    - Speech, 2004, Jan. 8 (Folder 41)
    - Pages of various speeches, undated
    - I. Conception of child as theorist, scientist, explorer..., undated, Notecards (Folder 42)
    - Accepted glibly-- (1) CPE's reputation for parent involvement..., undated, Notecards
    - Eval. Educ., Lay Bane! Educ. is society in..., undated, Notecards (Folder 43)
    - Vast subject, microcosm of contradiction..., undated, Notecards
    - We're in a fix today. We're about to embark on an accounting system..., undated, Notecards
    - Notes on Willen family finances, undated, Notecards
    - Miscellaneous materials with drafts, including business cards, envelope, etc. (Folder 44)
- Writings by others, 1981-2009, undated (Box 10)
  - Articles on Meier, 1981-2008, undated (Box 10)
    - General, 1981-2005, undated, (1 folder)
      - Wells, Jeff. (1981, June 18). PS 171 Teachers defend the reading test. New York Post (p. 15)., 2 copies
      - Schanberg, Sydney H. (1987, Oct. 16). Fresh Ideas for a City Dying from a Lack of Them. New York Newsday.
      - Ramirez, Antonio. (1987, Oct. 26). An Enlightened Principal Speaks Out. New York Teacher Bulletin, volume 29, number 5 (p. 15).
      - Coons, Phyllis. (1988, Mar. 6). Just the Facts--or Principals?. Boston Sunday Globe (pp. ?, A92)., 6 copies
      - (1988, Spring). Profiles: Ten Top Teachers Tell Their Trade Secrets. Instructor, High School issue (pp. 6-23)., 2 copies
        See also: Articles about Debbie/CPE/CCE-91/92, by Debbie, 1 copy
      - (1988, Dec. 9). National Standards Debated at TC. Columbia University Record, volume 14, number 14 (pp. 1, 3, 6)., 2 copies (Box 3)
      - Karp, Stan. (ca. 1989). Changing Schools (pp. 86-91). (Box 10)
      - Brownstein, Ronald and Nina J. Easton. (1990, Nov. 11). Where is Mr. Smith Now that We Need Him?. Los Angeles Times Magazine (pp. 13-20, 38)., 3 copies
      - Harper, Amy. (1990, Fall). Evolution of an Educator. Antiochian (pp. 17-18).
      - Chrysler Corporation. (1992, Mar. 16). Amazing Americans. Time., 2 copies; See also: Master copies of articles, 1 copy
      - Glazer, Nathan. (1992, Autumn). No Excuses for Failure: Urban Schools in Transition. City Journal (pp. 24-31).
      - Hoban, Phoebe. (1992, Dec. 21-28). Old School Ties. New York (pp. 77-78).
      - Lockwood, Anne Turnbaugh. (1993, Summer). Standards vs. Standardization. National Standards, number 11 (pp. 7-9).
      - (1994, Mar. 3). The Right Questions about School. Riverdale Press., 3 copies
      - Berne, Robert. (1994, Sept. 11). Power to the Parents: How Much is Enough? New York Newsday (pp. A41-A42)., 3 copies
      - Berne, Robert. (1994, Sept. 11). Power to the Parents: How Much is Enough? New York Newsday (pp. A41-A42)., 3 copies (Box 3)
      - Wallis, Claudia. (1994, Oct. 31). A Class of Their Own. Time (pp. 53-61). (Box 10)
      - Kaminer, Ariel;; Larissa MacFarquhar; and Liesl Schillinger. (1995, Jan. 30). The 100 Smartest New Yorkers. New York (pp. 40-53)., 3 copies
      - Traub, James. (1995, Sept-Oct.). It's Elementary. School Leader (pp. 37-40, 58, 60)., 3 copies
      - Zuber, Martha. (1996, Dec.). Les sciences de l'education aux Etats-Unis. Sciences Humaines, number 67.
      - (1997, Spring). Deborah Meier: Democracy in Action. New Leaders for Tomorrow's Schools.
      - Gardner, Howard. (1999, May 4). Varied Paths to a Good Education. Christian Science Monitor (p. 15). (Box 3)
      - Immarigeon, Russ. (2000, July 3). One Size does not Fit All, Says Education Expert. Independent (p. 9).
      - Gross, Jane. (2002, Sept. 3). A Skeptical and Distant Eye on the Schools. New York Times (p. B2)., 2 copies
      - Gross, Jane. (2002, Sept. 3). A Skeptical and Distant Eye on the Schools. New York Times (p. B2)., 2 copies (Box 10)
      - Mathews, Jay. (2002, Oct. 15). Star Educator Decries Emphasis on Testing. Washington Post (p. A9)., 4 copies
      - Mathews, Jay. (2002, Oct. 15). Star Educator Decries Emphasis on Testing. Washington Post (p. A9)., 4 copies (Box 3)
      - Rosenberg, Merri. (2003, Feb.). A Conversation with Deborah Meier. Education Update. (Box 10)
      - MacDonald, Liz and Rachel Moulton. (2003-2004). Education. Noteworthy Alumni, volume 3 (p. 11).
      - Horn, Jim. (2005, June). State Officials Lead Resistance to 'No Child Left Behind.' Substance, volume 30, number 10 (pp. 1, 25). (Box 3)
      - Gladstone, Valerie. She's Retooled the City's Schools. Undated. (Box 10)
    - Reports on events at which Meier spoke, 1988-2003, undated, (1 folder)
      - (1988, Apr. 1). The Essential Deborah Meier. Public Education Alert, volume 2, number 1 (p. 2)., 2 copies
      - (1989, Oct. 20). Reform in New York. Honolulu Advertiser (p. R14).
      - (1993, Spring). To Respect Children: 'Imagine How Others See the World.' Holmes Group Forum, volume 7, number 3 (pp. 1, 23-24)., 2 copies
      - (1993, Dec. 16-22). Teachers Parents Learn Together. Gazette., 2 copies
      - Cohen, Muriel. (1995, May 14). NYC Educator Envisions Schools that Offer Parents a Choice. Boston Globe (pp. 84-85) (Box 1)
      - Capparet, LeRoy A.;; Robert W. Carr; and Michael J. Schippani. (1995, Dec. 3). Improving Our Schools Requires Vision, Dialogue. Ann Arbor News. (Box 10)
        Includes poster for a talk by Meier
      - Branam, Judson. (1995, Dec. 6). What If…? Educational Reformer to Speak Here and Raise that Question. Ann Arbor News (pp. B1, B5)., 2 copies
      - Branam, Judson. (1995, Dec. 10). Drive for Smaller Schools Gets Push. Ann Arbor News (pp. B1-B2).
      - Smith, Andrew C. (1995, Dec. 14). Smaller Schools are Not Necessarily Better. Ann Arbor News.
        See also: Meier's response
      - (1995). Public Education Forum Planned. Washtenaw Jewish News.
      - (1996, May). Skepticism, Empathy, Hope, and Respect. Education Update, volume 38, number 3 (p. 5)., 2 copies
      - Sachar, Emily. (1996, Summer-Fall). New York City Roundtable: Which Way to Quality Schools? Ford Foundation Report (pp. 12-15).
      - (1995-1996). Visitors to the Klingenstein Programs (p. 12).
      - Graves, Bill. (1997, Mar. 18). A Model for Reform in Education. Oregonian.
      - Caldwell, Frances. (1997, Mar.). Educator Meier to Speak at PSU. Woman's Journal, volume 5, number 3 (p. 16)., 2 copies (Box 3)
      - Wolf, Andrew. (1997, June 19-25). Speaking at Fieldston, Noted Educator Urges Private School Standards in Public Education: for Schools like M.S. 141 and Kennedy, Deborah Meier Advocates Changes. Riverdale Review, volume 4, number 35 (pp. 1, 22).
      - Wolf, Andrew. (1997, June 19-25). Speaking at Fieldston, Noted Educator Urges Private School Standards in Public Education: for Schools like M.S. 141 and Kennedy, Deborah Meier Advocates Changes. Riverdale Review, volume 4, number 35 (pp. 1, 22). (Box 10)
      - (1998, Summer). A Celebration of Teaching. Appian (pp. 24-25).
      - (1999, Fall). Creating a Community in Schools. News and Notes, volume 5, number 3 (pp. 1-2)., 2 copies
      - (2001, June). School Board for Each School. Education Update (p. 8).
      - Davidson, Susie. (2001, June 29-July 5). Local Principal is a Vocal Critic of MCAS Testing. Jewish Advocate (p. 17).
        Includes note and business card
      - Davidson, Susie. (2001, June 29-July 5). Local Principal is a Vocal Critic of MCAS Testing. Jewish Advocate (p. 17). (Box 3)
      - Adair, Jeff. (2002, May 8). Urging Teachers to Speak Out. Metrowest Daily News (pp. B1, B4). (Box 10)
      - (2002-2003, Winter). TC BookTalk: Deborah Meier. TC Today (p. 13)., 2 copies (Box 3)
      - Dujardin, Richard C. Bring Generations Together in Reinvention of Schools, Leading Educator Urges. Journal-Bulletin. Undated (Box 10)
    - Interviews with Meier, 1987-2008, undated, (2 folders) (Box 10)
      - Foster, Catherine. (1987, Oct. 30). Prestige Prize for a Principal: MacArthur Grant Honors Deborah Meier--and her Innovative School. Christian Science Monitor, volume 78, number 236 (pp. 19-20)., 3 copies
      - Foster, Catherine. (1987, Oct. 30). Prestige Prize for a Principal: MacArthur Grant Honors Deborah Meier--and her Innovative School. Christian Science Monitor, volume 78, number 236 (pp. 19-20)., 3 copies (Box 3)
      - Barthe, Patte. (1989, Nov.). Socrates and East Harlem. Basic Education, volume 34, number 3 (pp. 13-15)., 2 copies (Box 10)
      - (1991, Jan./Feb.). Taking Risks and Making Sense: An Interview with Deborah Meier. Harvard Education Letter, volume 7, number 1 (pp. 4-6)., 4 copies
      - Morton, Brian. (1991, Summer). Bush and the Schools: A Hard Look. Dissent (pp. 329-331).
      - Avenoso, Karen. (1994, June 26). Taking Stock of Schools. Daily News (p. 3)., 2 copies
      - Avenoso, Karen. (1994, June 26). Taking Stock of Schools. Daily News (p. 3)., 2 copies (Box 3)
      - Scherer, Marge. (1994, Summer). On Schools Where Students Want to Be: A Conversation with Deborah Meier. Educational Leadership (pp. 4-8). (Box 10)
      - Lamb, Lynette. (1995, Aug. 22).
      - Larsen, Elizabeth. (1995, Aug. 28). [Replies to Elizabeth Larsen re the Lens Interview].
      - Harris, Philip. (1996, Summer). Technos Interview: Deborah W. Meier. Technos, volume 5, number 2 (pp. 4-8)., 5 copies
      - Dykman, Ann. (1997, Feb.). Interview with Deborah Meier. Techniques, volume 72, number 2 (pp. 30-35).
      - Bogen, Mitch. (1999, Fall). The Power that Comes from Real Standards. ESR Forum, volume 16, number 3 (pp. 4-5, 11)., 4 copies
      - Wingert, Pat. (2000, June 12). Do Tests Hurt Poor Kids? A Noted Reformer Argues Against High-Stakes Exams. Newsweek (p. 79).
      - Vaishnav, Arnold. (2001, Sept. 2). Principal Airs Views on Education. Boston Globe (p. B8)., 3 copies
      - Paulson, Amanda. (2002, Sept. 17). A Plea to Trust Schools--Not Just Tests. Christian Science Monitor (p. 14)., 5 copies
      - Paulson, Amanda. (2002, Sept. 17). A Plea to Trust Schools--Not Just Tests. Christian Science Monitor (p. 14)., 5 copies (Box 3)
      - (2008, Apr.). Spotlight on… Deborah Meier. Education Forum, volume 3, number 8 (pp. 2-3). (Box 10)
      - Classroom Teacher Network Interview with Deborah Meier. Undated
    - Book Chapters, 1999-2003, undated, (1 folder)
      - Kozol, Jonathan. (1999).
      - Graff, Gerry. (1999). Chapter 8: Progressive Education with Standards.
        Includes letter from Gerald Graff
      - Graff, Gerry. (2003). 14: Deborah Meier's Progressive Traditionalism. Clueless in Academe (pp. 261-274)., 2 copies
  - Papers and reports on Meier, 1987-2004, undated, (1 folder) (Box 10)
    - Engelken, Regina. (1987). Back-to-Basics Backlash Could Ruin Public Education, Warns Teacher of Teachers.
    - Stern, Zelda. (1996). Interview with Deborah Meier.
    - McEntee, Grace. (1996). Report to Building Capacity.
    - Levin, Jennifer. (2003). Deborah Meier: A Pioneer in Modern Education.
    - Jones, Courtney. (2003). The Power of Their Ideas.
    - DiBrienza, Jennifer;; Hilary Dolan;; Carla M. Roach; and Eric Westendorf. (2004). Deborah Meier: A Case Study.
    - Hathorn, Beth. [untitled]. Undated
  - Writings on Theodore R. Sizer's Horace's Compromise, 1983-1987, (1 folder) (Box 10)
    - (1983, Nov. 16). The Teacher as Coach: Fewer Facts, More Learning. Education Week (pp. 12-13). (Box 3)
    - Selected Quotes from Horace's Dilemma by Ted Sizer--as they appeared in Education Week, 1983, Nov. 16, 2 copies (Box 10)
    - Sizer, Theodore R. (1984, Mar.). Compromises. Educational Leadership (pp. 34-37)., 2 copies
    - M., T. (1985, May 29). Common Principles Link Coalition Members' Efforts to Reshape Their Schools' Programs. Education Week, volume 4, number 36.
      See also: MacArthur Fellowship; binder of recommendations, resumes, articles, etc., 1 copy
    - M., T. (1985, May 29). Essential Schools: Putting Theory into Practice. Education Week, volume 4, number 36., 2 copies
    - Kliebard, Herbert M. (1987, Spring). Compromise and Diversity in the American High School. History of Education Quarterly, volume 27, number 1 (pp. 89-100).
    - Maeroff, Gene I. (1984, Feb. 8). Report Calls for Limiting High School Enrollment. New York Times (p. A16).
    - Keller, Jon. Theodore Sizer Wants to Stamp Out Cookie-Cutter Education by Making High School Voluntary (pp. 243-247). ca. 1984
    - Olson, Lynn. (1987, Feb. 18). 'Less Is More:' Coalition Rethinking the Basic Design of Schools. Education Week, volume 6, number 21 (pp. 1, 22-25).
  - General, 1991-2009, undated, (1 folder) (Box 10)
    Arranged alphabetically by author
    - Cohen, Annette Wallach. (1991, June). Excitement in East Harlem. AI InHouse (pp. 4, 8).
      See: Writings by Deborah Meier, 1 copy; Writings removed from binder pockets, 1 copy
    - Haney, Walt. (1991). We Must Take Care: Fitting Assessments to Functions. Expanding Student Assessment (pp. 142-163).
    - Hiro, Sachiya. (1993, Feb. 24). Worth Noting. Education Week.
    - Pariser, Emanuel. (1992, May). In Search of Outcomes: Alternative School Graduates in the Real World. Changing Schools, volume 20, number 2 (pp. 1-7).
    - (1993, Nov. 19). Fencing Classes., 2 copies
    - Piercy, Marge. To Be of Use. Circles on the Water. Undated
    - Powell, Arthur G. (1997). Interests of Mind: Mapping the Territory, Introduction.
    - (1997, Spring/Summer). Raising Standards, volume 5, number 1.
    - Ravitch, Diane. (2003, Jan. 19). Taking the Public Out of Public Schools.
    - (2003, Dec. 23). TCRecord Kilpatrick Collection contents.
    - Thornburg, David. (2008, Mar. 24). On Math and Science Ed.
    - (2009, Spring). Unschooling, Reschooling, and Alternative Schooling--Options for Everyone. Education Revolution, volume 21, number 1.
    - Wolk, Ronald A. Alternative Answer. Undated
    - Wood, George. Whose Child Left Behind? Undated
    - Wood, George. No Excuses. Undated
- Professional activities, 1968-2009, undated (Box 10)
  - Teachers' strike, school decentralization, and L.I.D, 1967-1969, undated (Box 10)
    Includes flyer, proposal, and statements
  - Early school experiments, 1968-1972, undated (Box 11)
    - IS 44 pilot classes parent, 1968-1972, undated
      - Correspondence regarding Meier's criticism of segregation and tracking, 1968
      - Summer Tutorial Program reports and supporting documentation, 1968, undated
      - Sub-school pilot class proposals, 1969-1972, undated
      - Correspondence regarding IS44 pilot classes, 1969, undated
      - Ethnic composition and lists of students for pilot classes, 1970, undated
      - Parents' meeting reports, executive board meeting report, student council report, and miscellaneous other reports on teacher, parent, and student trips and the program, 1969-1971, undated
      - Student assessments, undated
      - Schedules for courses and parent volunteers, undated
    - PS 144 open corridor classes teacher, 1969-1972, undated
      - Correspondence, 1970-1971, undated
        - Requests to visit, 1970-1971, undated
        - Letters of appreciation for visits, 1970-1971, undated
        - Responses from Meier to requests to visit, 1970, undated
        - Miscellaneous, 1970-1971, undated
          Includes requests for positions, requests for information, letters of encouragement, and letters regarding staff changes
      - Lists, invoices, and packing slips for school supplies and books, 1971, undated
      - Funding, 1969-1972, undated
        Includes request for funds, bank account contract, and correspondence regarding donations
      - Miscellaneous, undated
    - PS 84 open classroom advisor, undated
      Includes history of the program, teacher schedules and notes on objectives
  - District three school board, 1974-1977 (Box 11)
    Includes three campaign pamphlets, policy statement, essay Why I'm Not Running Again for CSB 3
    See also: Writings by Deborah Meier and MacArthur Fellowship; binder of recommendations, resumes, articles, etc., 1 printed copy in each of Why I'm Not Running Again for CSB 3 essay
  - Central Park East (CPE), 1974-2001, undated (Box 11)
    - General, 1977-2000, undated
      - Articles, 1977-2000, undated
        - On CPE, 1977-2005, undated, (4 folders)
          - Berlin, Michael J. (1977, Nov. 9). Where Kids & Teachers Have Made it Work. New York Post (p. 35)., 5 copies
          - Berlin, Michael J. (1977, Nov. 9). Where Kids & Teachers Have Made it Work. New York Post (p. 35)., 5 copies (Box 3)
          - Central Park East staff. (1979, Mar. 20). Hurrah Team! New York Post (p. 22).
          - Crossman, Elizabeth. (1979, Nov. 12). Not Your Ordinary School Lunch. The Westsider., 2 copies (Box 11)
          - Russo, Constance. (1980, Jan. 17). Central Park East: Where Education is an Adventure. East Side Express., 3 copies
          - (1980, June 16). Central Park East. New York (p. 23-29).
          - Flanders, Rickie. (1981, Feb. 8). One of New York City's Alternative Schools: Central Park East--A Miniature Community. New York Teacher, volume 22, number 22., 10 copies
          - Flanders, Rickie. (1981, Feb. 8). One of New York City's Alternative Schools: Central Park East--A Miniature Community. New York Teacher, volume 22, number 22., 10 copies (Box 3)
          - Lazarre, Jane. (1983, Feb. 15). Class Struggles. The Village Voice (pp. 11-12, 14-15, 32, 34). (Box 10)
            See: MacArthur Fellowship; binder of recommendations, resumes, articles, etc., 1 copy; Oversize 3, folder 10
          - Anderson, Susan Heller and Carroll, Maurice. (1984, Feb. 4). Music's Charms. New York Times (p. 27).
          - Englund, Will. (1985, May 12). Teaching Less--But Teaching Better. Baltimore Sun, volume 85, number 19 (p. 1, 10A-11A)., 2 copies
          - Englund, Will. (1985, May 12). Teaching Less--But Teaching Better. Baltimore Sun, volume 85, number 19 (p. 1, 10A-11A)., 2 copies (Box 3)
          - Seletsky, Alice. (1985, May 25). Where the Action Is. The Nation (pp. 634-638)., 3 copies (Box 11)
            Includes note from Meier
          - Henderson, Keith. (1986, Apr. 18). Restructuring Education at a Harlem School. Christian Science Monitor (pp. 21-22)., 2 copies
          - Youngwood, Jonathan. (1986, Apr. 30). Harlem Students Visit Brown Kids from Sizer Inspired School. Brown Daily Herald, volume 120, number 61 (p. 5)., 4 copies (Box 11)
          - Youngwood, Jonathan. (1986, Apr. 30). Harlem Students Visit Brown Kids from Sizer Inspired School. Brown Daily Herald, volume 120, number 61 (p. 5)., 4 copies (Box 3)
          - Perlez, Jane. (1987, May 24). A Harlem School Stresses the Basics. New York Times (p. 42)., 4 copies (Box 11)
          - Perlez, Jane. (1987, May 24). A Harlem School Stresses the Basics. New York Times (p. 42)., 4 copies (Box 3)
          - Hechinger, Fred M. (1987, July 7). The Short Life of the Success Story. New York Times., 4 copies (Box 11)
          - Cohen, Muriel. (1987, Dec. 18). A Leader Among the Followers: Harlem Principal Debbie Meier is an Advocate for Educational Reform. Boston Globe (pp. 91, 94)., 2 copies
          - Cohen, Muriel. (1987, Dec. 18). A Leader Among the Followers: Harlem Principal Debbie Meier is an Advocate for Educational Reform. Boston Globe (pp. 91, 94)., 2 copies (Box 3)
          - Lewis, Anne C. (1988, Sept.). America's 10 Best School Programs. Ladies' Home Journal (pp. 65-68, 73-75, 194)., 2 copies (Box 11)
          - Auletta, Ken. (1988, Oct. 2). She's Got a Way of Making the Kids Think. Daily News (p. 42)., 5 copies
          - Auletta, Ken. (1988, Oct. 2). She's Got a Way of Making the Kids Think. Daily News (p. 42)., 5 copies (Box 3)
          - Cook, Karen. (1988, Oct.). Principals with Interest. Savvy (pp. 62-66, 108-112)., 3 copies (Box 11)
          - Perry, Nancy J. (1988, Nov. 7). Saving the Schools: How Business Can Help. Fortune (pp. 42-56)., 4 copies
          - (1988). The 1988 Alumni Association Awards.
          - Kirp, David L. (1989, Jan.). Education: The Movie. Mother Jones, volume 14, number 1 (pp. 34-45)., 5 copies
          - Cohen, Muriel. (1989, Mar. 10). In East Harlem, a School of Choice. Boston Globe, volume 235, number 69 (p. 2). (Box 3)
          - Brislin, Tom. (1989, Oct. 16). Celebrated New York Principal Calls School No Preparation for Real World. Honolulu Advertiser (p. A2)., 2 copies (Box 11)
          - Fiske, Edward B. (1989). Lessons: The Alternative Schools of Famous District 4: Accolades and Better Attendance are not Enough (p. B8)., 4 copies
          - Hearth, Amy Hill. (1990, Apr. 1). For Teen-Agers the Lessons of Africa. New York Times.
          - Hechinger, Fred M. (1990, Nov. 7). About Education. New York Times.
          - Poinsett, Alex. (1990, Nov.). Education Flowers in New York Ghetto. Catalyst (pp. 8-10)., 2 copies
          - Goldberg, Mark F. 1990, Dec.-1991, Jan.). Portrait of Deborah Meier. Educational Leadership, volume 48, number 4 (pp. 26-28)., 6 copies
            See also: Articles about Debbie/CPE/CCE-91/92, by Debbie, 1 printed
          - Barko, Naomi. (1991, Jan.). Salute to Success. New Choices, volume 31, number 1 (pp. 81-83)., 4 copies
          - (1991, Mar. 2). Choice in Public Schools Can Work. Berkshire Eagle (p. A6)., 2 copies
          - Tashman, Billy. (1992, Jan. 21). Hobson's Choice: Free-market Education Plan Vouches for Bush's Favorite Class. The Village Voice.
          - James, Mary Galloway. (1992, Apr.). I Came. I Saw. I was Conquered. BPI Newsletter (pp. 1-7).
          - Clinchy, Evans. (1992, Spring). An Urban High School in the 'Kindergarten Tradition': Alternative Concept Schooling at Central Park East Secondary School in New York City. Equity and Choice, volume 8, number 3 (pp. 24-30)., 2 copies
          - Matos, Lucy. (1992, Summer). The Role of Leadership in a Democratically Run School. Connections, volume 3, number 3 (pp. 1, 12).
          - Tashman, Billy. (1992, Sept. 24). Choice: Oases or Wastelands. New York Newsday.
          - Bracey, Gerald W. (1992, Nov.). Quality and Differences. Phi Delta Kappan (pp. 263-265)., 2 copies
          - Pochoda, Elizabeth. (1992, Dec. 21). Women and Children Last. The Nation (p. 774).
          - Hoban, Phoebe. (1992, Dec. 21-28). Old School Ties. New York (pp. 77-78).
          - Mosle, Sara. (1993, Oct. 31). The Will to Make a Difference. Washington Post Education Review (pp. 14-15).
          - Cohen, Muriel. (1994, Sept. 25). Charter in Hand, They Now Seek Pilot Status. Boston Globe (pp. B22, B24). (Box 3)
          - Smith, Hedrick. (1995, June 11). This School Teaches Real Life. Parade Magazine (p. 8)., 3 copies (Box 11)